Guide to the Papers of George L. Mosse (1918-1999), 1780-2001 AR 25137 / MF 671
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
- Series II: Writings and Research, 1750-2001; 25.3 linear feet
  - Subseries 3: Lectures and Conference Papers, undated, 1946-1998; 6.25 linear feet
    Subseries 3: Lectures and Conference Papers concerns George L. Mosse's lectures and talks, including those given at the universities where he was employed.
    Lectures and Papers contains unpublished manuscripts mostly used by Mosse at talks he gave during various conferences or symposiums or for groups. The most prominent topic covered in the writings here is fascism; other topics include nationalism, Jewish history and culture, homosexuality, and masculinity. Folders labeled Speaking Engagements contain announcements in the form of brochures, flyers, and posters advertising his lectures at various universities and for various groups.
    Course material used by George L. Mosse in the courses he taught includes typed and handwritten lectures and notes, copies of examination and paper assignment questions, and syllabi, as well as a few letters from students and one paper by a student of Mosse's Western Civilization course. The majority of materials in this section date from his time teaching at the University of Wisconsin at Madison. Notes on his course Tudor and Stuart England, however, are from his time at the University of Iowa. This was one of the first courses he taught. Several of his courses were overview courses of European and Western history. Other courses focus on Jewish history, the history of manliness, and the Fin de Siècle. There is some material on the course Cultural History, however, the dearth of information makes it difficult to ascertain if Mosse himself taught this course.
    - A) Lectures and Papers
      - Speaking Engagements, undated (Box 15, Folder 31)
      - Speaking Engagements, 1948-1974 (Box 15, Folder 32)
      - Speaking Engagements, 1975-1979 (Box 15, Folder 33)
      - Speaking Engagements, 1980-1984 (Box 15, Folder 34)
      - Speaking Engagements, 1985-1989 (Box 15, Folder 35)
      - Speaking Engagements, 1990-1994 (Box 15, Folder 36)
      - Speaking Engagements, 1995-1998 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Absolutism and Enlightenment, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Anti-Democratic Thought and the Rise of the National Socialism, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Anti-Fascism, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Anti-Fascist Resistance: Myth or Reality Colloquium, 1969-1973 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - The Appeal of Nazi Culture, 1970? (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Assimilation of Youth Culture in Germany, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Berlin Ausstellung, 1985-1987 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - Berlin 1900, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - Das Bild des Mannes. Zur Konstruktion der modernen Männlichkeit - Book Presentation, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - Bildung, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - Brandeis Lecture, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - Cambridge Talks, 1989-1990 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Can Nationalism be Saved? About Zionism, Rightful and Unjust Nationalism, 1996? (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - Can Nationalism be Saved? About Zionism, Rightful and Unjust Nationalism - Background Material, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - Can Nationalism be Saved? About Zionism, Rightful and Unjust Nationalism - The Friends of the Milton Center, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - Can Nationalism be Saved? About Zionism, Rightful and Unjust Nationalism - Yad Chaim Weizmann Paper, 1995-1996 (Box 16, Folder 17)
      - Change in European Opinion, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
      - Chapel Talks - State University of Iowa, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - Christianity and Politics, undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
      - Christianity and Reason of State, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
      - Cold War or Coexistence? - American Historical Association Comment, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 22)
      - Commencement Address, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 23)
      - Concept of Democracy - The Liberal Inheritance and the National Socialist Public Sphere, undated (Box 16, Folder 24)
      - Conquest of the Skies, undated (Box 16, Folder 25)
      - Contemporary Trends, 1958-1959 (Box 16, Folder 26)
      - Cornell Lectures, undated (Box 16, Folder 27)
      - The Counter-type, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 28)
      - The Creation of the New Man - Cornell Lectures - Elizabeth Hull's Class, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 29)
      - Cultural History, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 30)
      - Culture and Civilization: The Function of the Historian, undated (Box 16, Folder 31)
      - Culture of Western Europe - Maastricht, undated (Box 16, Folder 32)
      - Decadence Seminar, undated (Box 16, Folder 33)
      - Deutsch-jüdisches Bildungsbürgertum, undated (Box 16, Folder 34)
      - The End of an Epoch? The Leo Baeck Institute after the War - LBI Lecture, 1995? (Box 16, Folder 35)
      - English Constitutional History, undated (Box 16, Folder 36)
      - Enlightenment to Romanticism, undated (Box 16, Folder 37)
      - Entartete Kunst, undated, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 38)
      - European Fascism - Cambridge Lectures, 1976-1990 (Box 16, Folder 39)
      - European Fascism - Lectures, undated (Box 16, Folder 40)
      - European Fascism - Lectures - Not Used, undated, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 41)
      - European Political Thought, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - The European Right as a Mass Movement: Some Hypotheses, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Exile - Autobiography, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Exile - Liberating Force, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Expressionism and Brutality, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Facing Mass Death, The Trench Generation and the Myth of the War Experience, 1988-1989 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Fascinating Fascism, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Fascism and Consensus, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Fascism and History, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Fascism and Sexuality, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Fascism as a Cultural Movement, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Fascism as a Nationalist Movement: The Missing Link, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Fascism Colloquium, 1969-1971 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Fascist Aesthetics and Society: Some Considerations, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Fin de Siècle and the Decline of Morals, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Fin de Siècle - Challenge and Response, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - The First World War and the Flight from Reason, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Foreign Service Seminar - Jerusalem, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Fraternity Talks, 1956, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Freedom Forum Lecture, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - French Revolution and Fascism, undated, 1987-1990 (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - Future Lectures, 1976-1977 (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Gerda Lerner Speech, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - German Jews - Lecture, undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - German Jews and Liberalism in Retrospect, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - A Ghost Come Alive, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Growing Up Jewish, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 27)
      - Hadassah Lecture, 1992, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - Harvard Symposium, 1983-1985 (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - Heimat, undated (Box 17, Folder 30)
      - Hillel Talk, undated (Box 17, Folder 31)
      - Historikerstreit, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 32)
      - Historiography, undated (Box 17, Folder 33)
      - History Conference Lecture, undated (Box 17, Folder 34)
      - History of Anti-Semitism - Hebrew University, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 35)
      - The Holocaust and Modern Manners and Morals, undated (Box 17, Folder 36)
      - The Holocaust, Death, and Memories of War, undated (Box 17, Folder 37)
      - Holocaust Lectures, 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 38)
      - Homosexuality and French Fascism, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 39)
      - Die Idee des "Neuen Mannes" in modernen revolutionären Bewegungen - Jüdische Volkshochschule Berlin, 1988-1989 (Box 17, Folder 40)
      - The Importance of Gay Literature, undated (Box 17, Folder 41)
      - Intellectuals and Politics, undated (Box 17, Folder 42)
      - International Symposium in Memory of George Lichtheim, 1974-1976 (Box 17, Folder 43)
      - Iowa Public Lectures, 1946-1952? (Box 17, Folder 44)
      - Iowa Public Lectures - Hillel Talks, undated, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 45)
      - Iowa Public Lectures - Israel, undated (Box 17, Folder 46)
      - Is Fascism Alive? - Australian Broadcasting Corporation, undated (Box 17, Folder 47)
      - Jewish Alternatives and Jewish Youth: Socialism and, undated (Box 17, Folder 48)
      - The Jews and the Civic Religion of Nationalism, undated (Box 17, Folder 49)
      - Jewish Emancipation: Between Bildung and Respectability - Clark College, undated (Box 17, Folder 50)
      - Jost Hermand Paper, undated (Box 17, Folder 51)
      - Jud Süss, undated, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 52)
      - The Kaffeehausjude and the Kaftanjude - Two Models of Jewish Insanity: a Discussion of Causes and Cures, undated (Box 17, Folder 53)
      - Landscape Architects' Lecture, undated (Box 17, Folder 54)
      - The Left and the War Experience in Germany (With a Brief French Comparison) - Cornell, undated (Box 17, Folder 55)
      - Left-Wing Intellectuals and the Jewish Problems: the 1930s and the 1960s, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Liberale[s] Erbe und die national-sozialistische Öffentlichkeit, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Luther College Lecture, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Malhoh Lecture, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Manliness and the Great War - Paper, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Manliness and War - Lecture, 1994? (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Martin Luther and Politics, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Masculinity and Decadence, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Masculinity and Decadence - London Lecture, 1993? (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Mass Politics and the Political Liturgy of Nationalism, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - The Masses and Historical Consciousness, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Max Nordau Colloquium, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Max Nordau, Liberalism and the New Jew, 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Modern Anti-Semitism, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Modern Anti-Semitism: Failure of the Enlightenment, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - The Modern Construction of Masculinity, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - The Myth of the War Experience, 1986-1987 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - National Self-Representation during the 1930s in Europe and the United States, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - National Self-Representation during the 1930s in Europe and the United States - Gramsci Paper, undated, 1976-1988 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - National Socialism and Germany Today, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - The National Socialists Persecution of Gays, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 21)
      - Nationalism, undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
      - Nationalism and Patriotism, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 23)
      - Nationalism and War, undated (Box 18, Folder 24)
      - Nationalism - Israel, undated (Box 18, Folder 25)
      - Nationalism - Mühlheim Talk, undated (Box 18, Folder 26)
      - Nationhood and Diaspora, undated (Box 18, Folder 27)
      - New Home Club Lecture, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 28)
      - New Man Lecture, undated (Box 18, Folder 29)
      - New Man Lecture - English and German, undated (Box 18, Folder 30)
      - NSA Lecture, undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
      - Old Lectures, undated (Box 18, Folder 32)
      - Old Lectures, 1950-1956 (Box 18, Folder 33)
      - Outsider - Lecture, undated (Box 18, Folder 34)
      - Pacifism, undated (Box 18, Folder 35)
      - The Philosophy of the Right, undated (Box 18, Folder 36)
      - Polish Academy Lecture, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 37)
      - Political Awakening: Berlin; Exile; and Anti-Fascist Movement - University of Kentucky, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 38)
      - Politisches Erwachen, Berlin, Das Exil und Antifaschistische Bewegung - Technische Universität Berlin, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 39)
      - Die Politische Anwendung der Geshichte, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 40)
      - Rabbi Manfred Swarensky Memorial, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 41)
      - Race and Sexuality, Bourgeois Society and the Outsider in the Nineteenth Century, 1982-1983 (Box 18, Folder 42)
      - Racism and Nationalism in Europe, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 43)
      - Racism Lecture, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 44)
      - A Re-Examination of the Liberties of Englishmen - Humanities Society Lecture, undated (Box 18, Folder 45)
      - Renaissance and Reformation, undated (Box 18, Folder 46)
      - Renaissance and Reformation, undated (Box 18, Folder 47)
      - Rome - Integration, undated (Box 18, Folder 48)
      - Rome Lecture, undated (Box 18, Folder 49)
      - Rushing to the Colors: On the History of Volunteers in War, undated (Box 18, Folder 50)
      - Russia and Homosexuality - Lecture 2 Notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 51)
      - Samuel Smiles Paper, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Scholars, Madmen and Luftmenschen: German Jews Between Bildung and Breakdown - Comments - Princeton University History Symposium, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Schule Schloss Salem - Lecture, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Shell-Shock as a Social Disease, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - SNIC Lecture, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Tel Aviv Lecture, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Them: Dangers of Normalcy, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Totalitarianism, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Der Totenkult der Nation, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Turin Lecture, 1990-1991 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Two Fin de Siècles - Minneapolis, after 1996 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Two Fin de Siècles and the Decline of Morals - Announcement, 1996 (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Unidentified Colloquium, 1968-1969 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Unidentified Lectures, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Unidentified Lectures - To Students, undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - The Universal Meaning of the Concept of Bildung, 1997-1998 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - University of Wisconsin - WHA Radio Project, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - Utopia, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - War Book - German Lecture - Book Tour, undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - Wars and Warriors, undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - Wartburg College, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - Weimar Culture, undated (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - Weimar Lecture - Jerusalem, undated (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - What is New about National Socialism - Cornell Lecture, undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - What Is Still Valid about Marx?, undated (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - Why did Pacifism Fail Between Two World Wars?, undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom Talk, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 24)
      - Zionist Nationalism, undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - B) Courses
      - Cultural History, 1947-1955, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 26)
      - Europe and the Modern World, undated (Box 19, Folder 27)
      - Europe and the Modern World - Between the Wars, undated (Box 19, Folder 28)
      - Europe and the Modern World - Correspondence, 1956-1975 (Box 19, Folder 29)
      - Europe and the Modern World - Examinations and Paper Assignments, 1956-1975 (Box 19, Folder 30)
      - Europe and the Modern World - Final Lecture, undated, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 31)
      - Europe and the Modern World - Revolutions of 1848, undated (Box 19, Folder 32)
      - Europe and the Modern World - Soviet Revolution, undated (Box 19, Folder 33)
      - Europe and the Modern World - Syllabi, 1955-1975 (Box 19, Folder 34)
      - European Cultural History (1610-1815) - Correspondence, undated, 1960, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 35)
      - European Cultural History (1610-1815) - Examinations and Paper Assignments, 1956-1986 (Box 19, Folder 36)
      - European Cultural History (1610-1815) - Syllabi, 1963-1979 (Box 19, Folder 37)
      - European Culture - Old Lectures, undated (Box 19, Folder 38)
      - European Culture 1600 to 1800, undated (Box 19, Folder 39)
      - European Culture 1600 to 1800 - Absolutism, undated (Box 19, Folder 40)
      - European Culture 1600 to 1800 - Baroque, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - European Culture 1815-1870, undated, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - European Culture 1815-1870 - Enlightenment and Pietism, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - European Culture 1815-1870 - Liberalism, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - European Culture 1815-1870 - Marxism, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - European Culture 1815-1870 - New Nationalism and Hegelianism, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - European Culture 1815-1870 - Romanticism, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - European Culture 1815-1900 - Syllabi and Examinations, 1956-1983 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - European Culture Since 1870 - Correspondence, 1957-1984 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - European Culture Since 1870 - Examinations and Paper Assignments, 1956-1984 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - European Culture Since 1870 - Old Lectures, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - European Culture Since 1870 - Old Lectures - Introductions and Summaries, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - European Culture Since 1870 - Old Lectures - Marxism and Communism, undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - European Culture Since 1870 - Old Lectures - Not Used, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - European Culture Since 1870 - Old Lectures - Romanticism, undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - European Culture Since 1870 - Syllabi, 1958-1989 (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - European Culture Since 1870 - Weimar, undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - European Intellectual History Since 1815, 1955-1960 (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - European Social and Intellectual History - Syllabi and Examinations, 1955-1960 (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - Examen Du Texts Graduate Seminar, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - Fascism Seminar, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - Fin de Siècle, undated (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - Fin de Siècle - Challenge and Response, undated (Box 20, Folder 23)
      - Fin de Siècle - Decadence, undated (Box 20, Folder 24)
      - Fin de Siècle - Final Lecture, undated (Box 20, Folder 25)
      - Fin de Siècle - Nietzsche, undated (Box 20, Folder 26)
      - Fin de Siècle - Not Used, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 27)
      - History 512 - Syllabi, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 28)
      - History of Manliness, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 29)
      - History of Manliness - Syllabi, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - History of Sexual Identity, 1979-1982, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Jewish History in the 19th and 20th Centuries, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Jewish History in the 19th and 20th Centuries - Assimilation, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Jewish History in the 19th and 20th Centuries - Correspondence, 1971-1987 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Jewish History in the 19th and 20th Centuries - Emancipation, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Jewish History in the 19th and 20th Centuries - Examinations and Paper Assignments, 1970-1987 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Jewish History in the 19th and 20th Centuries - Fascism, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Jewish History in the 19th and 20th Centuries - National Socialism and the Holocaust, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Jewish History in the 19th and 20th Centuries - Rise of Anti-Semitism, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Jewish History in the 19th and 20th Centuries - Syllabi, 1972-1988 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - Jewish History in the 19th and 20th Centuries - Zionism, undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - The Making of Modern Europe: 1500-1815, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - The Making of Modern Europe: 1500-1815 - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - The Making of Modern Europe: 1500-1815 - Enlightenment, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - The Making of Modern Europe: 1500-1815 - Reformation, undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
      - The Making of Modern Europe: 1500-1815 - Examinations, 1930-1973 (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - The Making of Modern Europe: 1500-1815 - Grades, 1958-1959 (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - The Making of Modern Europe: 1500-1815 - Student Letter (Box 21, Folder 19)
      - The Making of Modern Europe: 1500-1815 - Syllabi, 1956-1969 (Box 21, Folder 20)
      - Modern England, undated (Box 21, Folder 21)
      - Modern Jewry, 1987-1988 (Box 21, Folder 22)
      - Paris Seminars, undated (Box 21, Folder 23)
      - Problems in the Development of Calvinism, 1958-1959 (Box 21, Folder 24)
      - Pro-Seminar on National Socialism, undated (Box 21, Folder 25)
      - Sexuality Course - Jerusalem, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 26)
      - Sexuality Seminar, 1987-1988 (Box 21, Folder 27)
      - Tudor and Stuart England - Examination, 1949-1953 (Box 21, Folder 28)
      - Tudor and Stuart England - Stuart, undated (Box 21, Folder 29)
      - Tudor and Stuart England - Tudor, undated (Box 21, Folder 30)
      - Western Civilization, undated, 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 31)
      - Western Civilization - Correspondence, 1948-1950 (Box 21, Folder 32)
      - Western Civilization - Examinations, 1951-1958 (Box 21, Folder 33)
      - Western Civilization - Paper - Gellman, Elliot F.: Sorel on Syndacalism, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Subseries 4: Research Notes, undated, 1793-1999; 6.5 linear feet
    Alphabetical by book title or topic.
    Research notes are comprised of handwritten and typed notes made by Mosse and used in the production of his writings. Notes are separated into two parts:books and various. Books are divided by title and various is separated into five categories: First World War and the War Experience; Jewish History; Political Movements; Sexuality; and Other.
    Much of the notes, especially in the various section, are composed of photocopies of relevant newspaper clippings, magazine articles, papers, and short excerpts from books. Research notes for books such as Fallen Soldiers and The Image of Man also contain such items as well as original clippings. Other than clippings, most documents in this subseries are photocopied; dates given are those of the photocopied items and not the original documents.
    Research notes found under the heading Various cover a multitude of topics. The first category,a) First World War and the War Experience, contains information which relates not only to World War I, but also to the time period, such as England before World War I, Bildung, and the Boer War. World War I-related material focuses on such topics as volunteers, monuments and memorials, and celebrations.
    Material focusing on Jewish history mainly concerns German-Jewish history and culture. Some pertain to specific individuals or themes such as the Jewish Question and the Holocaust.
    Many of the notes on Political Movements pertain to right-wing movements such as National Socialism and Fascism, as well as to such topics as Racism. The one exception is the folder on the Communist movement in Germany. Notes which deal with the perception of sexuality in these movements are left in this section.
    Notes on Sexuality cover a variety of topics which Mosse used in his works. The greatest volume of notes are in the folders labeled "Sexuality." The most prominent topic in this section includes notes on homosexuality.
    The last part of this subseries,E) Other, holds topics not covered in earlier topics. Much of the material contained in this section relates to art. Mosse collected many reproductions of art, especially those reproduced in calendars or on postcards. Many of these postcards also have pictures of architecture or statues. Of possible interest to researchers, the folder concerning interment in Les Milles is a typed copy of entries written by Werner Bock.
    - A) Books
      - a) Confronting History
        - Research Notes, undated, 1959, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 1)